A Guide to the Edward Howard House Papers, 1873-1901
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Edward Howard House Papers 1873-1901
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10762
This collection contains ca. 250 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Provenance
The collection was transferred from the Barrett Twain papers,on May 23, 1988.
Scope and Content Information
Personal and business correspondence of House chiefly concerns a law suit over the stage production of "The prince and the pauper," an adaptation of Mark Twain's novel of the same name, and several subsequent, related law suits which did not directly involve Twain.
Other topics include House's health, the estate settlements of relatives, royalties, copyright, and his writing, particularly the anti-missionary novel "Yone Santo," and the stories "Midnight warning" and "The Claiborne twins". Events in Japan, particularly the 1894 conflict with China and subsequent Treaty of Shimonoseki are discussed. Edwin Booth, child actors, Ulysses S. Grant's world tour, and Ruralf Dittrich's concerts are mentioned.
Contents List
- Washington Hobart to House 1879 Jan 20, ALS, 3 p (Box 1)
- J.A. Bingham to House 1879 Feb 2, ALS, 2 p (Box 1)
- John Child to Washington Hobart 1879 Jun 6, ALS, 2 p (Box 1)
- J.H. Twichell to House 1879 Jun 9, ALS, 4 p (Box 1)
- Washington Hobart to John Child 1879 Jun 11, ALS, 2 p (Box 1)
- John Child to Washington Hobart 1879 Jun 12, ALS, 1 p (Box 1)
- Washington Hobart to John Child 1879 Jun 25, ALS, 1 p (Box 1)
- Washington Hobart to John Child 1879 Jul 3, ALS, 1 p (Box 1)
- Washington Hobart to John Child 1879 Jul 8, ALS, 1 p (Box 1)
- John Child to Washington Hobart 1879 Jul 10, ALS, 2 p (Box 1)
- Washington Hobart to John Child 1879 Jul 12, 1 p (Box 1)
- John Child to Washington Hobart 1879 Jul 14, ALS, 1 p (Box 1)
- J.R. Young to House 1879 Aug 27, ALS, 3 p (Box 1)
- J.R. Young to House 1879 [Aug or Sept], AL initialed, 1 p (Box 1)
- Simon V. Vedder to House 1879 Nov 25, ALS, 2 p (Box 1)
- J.R. Young to House 1879 Dec 1, ALS, 4 p (Box 1)
- Washington Hobart to House 1879 Dec 8, ALS, 3 p (Box 1)
- J. Russell Young to House 1879 Dec 19, ALS, 2 p (Box 1)
- Scribner's Magazine to House 1880 Mar 31, AL, 2 p (Box 1)
- J.G. Bennett to House 1880 Apr 17, LS, 2 p (Box 1)
- J.G. Bennett to House 1880 May 10, LS, 2 p (Box 1)
- J.G. Bennett to House 1880 Sep 12, ALS, 2 p (Box 1)
- J.G. Bennett to House 1880 Sep 16, L, 1 p (Box 1)
- J.G. Bennett to House 1880 Sep 20, ALS, 3 p (Box 1)
- J.G. Bennett to House 1880 Sep 25, ALS, 2 p (Box 1)
- A.H. Cole to House 1880 Sep 28, ALS, 6 p (Box 1)
- Yoshida Kiyonari to House 1880 Oct 2, ALS, 4 p (Box 1)
- J.G. Bennett to House 1880 Oct 6, ALS, 1 p (Box 1)
- J.G. Bennett to House 1880 Nov 5, ALS, 1 p (Box 1)
- Yoshida Kiyonari to House 1880 Nov 25, ALS, 3 p (Box 1)
- C.O. Shepard to House 1881 Mar 18, ALS, 3 p (Box 1)
- C.O. Shepard to House 1881 [Mar 19], ALS, 2 p (Box 1)
- C.O. Shepard to House 1881 Jul 24, ALS, 3 p (Box 1)
- C.O. Shepard to House 1881 Jul 28, ALS, 3 p (Box 1)
- C.O. Shepard to House 1881 Aug [Sunday], ALS, 3 p (Box 1)
- M.M. Barry to C.O. Shepard 1881 Sep 26, ALS, 6 p (Box 1)
- M.M. Barry to House 1881 Sep 26, ALS copy, 5 p (Box 1)
- C.O. Shepard to House 1881 Nov 15, ALS, 3 p (Box 1)
- Yoshida Kiyonari to House 1881 Dec 9, ALS, 4 p (Box 1)
- [C.O.] Shepard to E.H. House 1881 Dec 14, ALS, 3 p (Box 1)
- [C.O.] Shepard to House 1882 Nov 11, ALS, 3 p (Box 1)
- F. Brinkley to House 1883 Aug 29, ALS, 3 p (Box 1)
- F. Brinkley to House 1883 Sep 8, ALS, 2 p (Box 1)
- F. Brinkley to House 1883 Sep 18, ALS, 2 p (Box 1)
- F. Brinkley to House 1883 Sep 21, ALS, 1 p (Box 1)
- F. Brinkley to House 1883 Sep 23, ALS, 1 p (Box 1)
- F. Brinkley to House 1883 Nov 11, ALS, 2 p (Box 1)
- F. Brinkley to House 1883 Dec 9, ALS, 2 p (Box 1)
- J.W. Harper to House 1884 Feb 6, ALS, 4 p (Box 1)
- F. Brinkley to House 1884 Mar 24, ALS, 2 p (Box 1)
- F. Brinkley to House 1884 Mar 30, ALS, 1 p (Box 1)
- F. Brinkley to House 1884 Apr 4, ALS, 1 p (Box 1)
- S. Ishiwata to House 1884 Jun 20, ALS, 1 p (Box 1)
- F. Brinkley to House 1884 Jul 2, ALS, 1 p (Box 1)
- F. Brinkley to House 1884 Aug 15, ALS, 4 p (Box 1)
- F. Brinkley to House 1884 Aug 23, ALS, 2 p (Box 1)
- F. Brinkley to House 1884 Sep 6, ALS, 2 p (Box 1)
- F. Brinkley to House 1884 Sep 8, ALS, 4 p (Box 1)
- Joseph W. Harper to House 1884 Sep 19, ALS, 2 p (Box 1)
- F. Brinkley to House 1884 Oct 3, ALS, 2 p (Box 1)
- F. Brinkley to House 1884 Oct 17, ALS, 1 p (Box 1)
- F. Brinkley to House 1884 Nov 1, ALS, 1 p (Box 1)
- F. Brinkley to House 1884 Nov 15, ALS, 2 p (Box 1)
- H. Moss to House 1884 Dec 24, ALS, 3 p (Box 1)
- F. Brinkley to House 1885 Jan 18, ALS, 1 p (Box 1)
- F. Brinkley to House 1885 Mar 12, ALS, 8 p (Box 1)
- F. Brinkley to House 1885 Apr 6, ALS, 3 p (Box 1)
- J. Conder to House 1885 May 2, ALS, 2 p (Box 1)
- F. Brinkley to House 1885 May 9, ALS, 2 p (Box 1)
- F. Brinkley to House 1885 May 12, ALS, 1 p (Box 1)
- F. Brinkley to House 1885 May 17, ALS, 2 p (Box 1)
- F. Brinkley to House 1885 May [Wednesday], ALS, 2 p (Box 1)
- H. Longley to Dr. Tripler 1885 Aug 7, ALS, 2 p (Box 1)
  2nd p contains autograph receipt, 1885 Aug 7, Longley to Tripler.
- F. Brinkley to House 1885 Oct 28, ALS, 4 p (Box 1)
- H. Moss to House 1886 Jan 11, statement of account and ALS, 3 p (Box 1)
- H. Moss to House 1886 Jan 22, ALS, 4 p (Box 1)
- F. Brinkley to House 1886 Feb 20, ALS, 4 p (Box 1)
- Mrs. J.W. Harper to House 1886 Jun 28, ALS, 2 p (Box 1)
- Thomas Bailey Aldrich to House 1886 Nov 22, ALS, 2 p (Box 1)
- J.W. Harper to House 1886 Dec 2, ALS, 2 p (Box 1)
- F. Brinkley to House 1887 Jan 7, ALS, 4 p (Box 1)
- Thomas Bailey Aldrich to House 1887 Mar 12, ACardS (Box 1)
- Thomas Bailey Aldrich to House 1887 Apr 18, ALS, 2 p (Box 1)
- A.L. Burlingame [of Scribner's] to House 1887 Jun 3, ALS, 6 p (Box 1)
- Scribner's Magazine to House 1887 May 10, Jun 3, 2 L, 2 p (Box 1)
- W.H. Patten to House 1887 May 18, ALS, 1 p (Box 1)
- Thomas Bailey Aldrich to House 1887 Jun 2, ALS, 1 p (Box 1)
- Atlantic Monthly to House 1887 Jun 18 -1888 Jul 21, 12 form letters (Box 1)
- Benjamin H. Ticknor to House 1887 Jun 27, ALS, 1 p (Box 1)
- H. Moss to House 1887 Jun 30, ALS, 3 p (Box 1)
- J.W. Harper to House 1887 Jul 21, ALS, 3 p (Box 1)
- H. Moss to House 1887 Aug 26, ALS, 4 p (Box 1)
- H. Moss to House 1887 Oct 18, ALS, 4 p (Box 1)
- F. Brinkley to House 1887 Dec 9, ALS, 4 p (Box 1)
- H. Moss to House 1888 Jan 14, ALS, 3 p (Box 1)
- H. Moss to House 1888 Jan 24, ALS, 1 p (Box 1)
- Edward D'Arcy [?] to House 1888 Feb 17, ALS, 2 p (Box 1)
- Houghton, Mifflin to House 1888 Mar 7 - Jul 14, 8 ALS, 1 ADS contract (Box 1)
- H. Moss to House 1888 Apr 11, ALS, 2 p (Box 1)
- F. Brinkley to House 1888 May 19, ALS, 3 p (Box 1)
- draft of letter to Houghton, Mifflin, & Co., House 1888 Jun 6, 2 p (Box 1)
- E.L. Burlingame to House 1888 Jun 7, TLS, 1 p (Box 2)
- E.L. Burlingame to House 1888 Jun 11, TLS, 1 p (Box 2)
- Thomas Bailey Aldrich to House 1888 Jun 16, ALS, 2 p (Box 2)
- E.L. Burlingame to House 1888 Jun 27, TLS, 2 p (Box 2)
- C.P. Farrell to House 1888 Jul 9, ALS, 3 p (Box 2)
- H. Moss to House 1888 Jul 9, ALS, 2 p (Box 2)
- E.L. Burlingame to House 1888 Jul 14, ALS, 2 p (Box 2)
- Harper & Brothers to House 1888 Jul 18, ALS, 1 p (Box 1)
- A.R. Spofford to House 1888 Aug 4, ALS, 1 p (Box 2)
- H. Moss to House 1888 Aug 7, ALS, 4 p (Box 2)
- E.L. Burlingame to House 1888 Oct 3, TLS, 1 p (Box 2)
- eds., "Library of Amer. Lit.," to House 1888 Oct 12, L, 2 p (Box 2)
- E.L. Burlingame to House 1888 Oct 25, ALS, 2 p (Box 2)
- Celia Logan to House 1888 Dec 13, ALS, 4 p (Box 2)
- S.S. McClure to House 1889 Jan 18, TLS, 2 p (Box 2)
- A.R. Spofford to House 1889 Feb 12, ANS, 2 p (Box 2)
- F. Brinkley to House 1889 Feb 15, ALS, 5 p (Box 2)
- D.N. Richardson to House 1889 Feb 18, ALS, 1 p (Box 2)
- F. Brinkley to House 1889 Mar 11, ALS, 1 p (Box 2)
- A.R. Spofford to House 1889 Mar 21, NS (Box 2)
- E.L. Burlingame to House 1889 Mar 21, TLS, 1 p (Box 2)
- Robert G. Ingersoll to House 1889 Mar 29, ALS, 1 p (Box 2)
- J.N. Baker to House 1889 Mar 29, ALS, 1 p (Box 2)
- Robert G. Ingersoll to House [1889 ca.Mar 29], ALS, 1 p (Box 2)
- J.N. Baker to House 1889 Apr 1, ALS, 2 p (Box 2)
- A.R. Spofford to House 1889 Apr 12, ANS, 1 p (Box 2)
- Henry H. Anderson to House 1889 Apr 18, ALS, 2 p (Box 2)
- Daniel Frohman to House [1889] May 2, ALS, 1 p (Box 2)
- Henry H. Anderson to House 1889 May 8, TLS, 2 p (Box 2)
- F. Brinkley to House 1889 May 18, ALS, 4 p (Box 2)
- Robert Belford to House 1889 Jun 12, ALS, 2 p (Box 2)
- E.L. Burlingame to House 1889 Jun 18, TLS, 3 p (Box 2)
- Chandos Fulton to House 1889 Jun 21, ALS, 3 p (Box 2)
  extract of letter from Clemens to H. Wall
- S.S. McClure to House 1889 Jul 5, TLS, 1 p (Box 2)
- E.L. Burlingame to House 1889 Jul 11, TLS, 1 p (Box 2)
- S.S. McClure to House 1889 Jul 15, TLS, 1 p (Box 2)
- S.S. McClure to House 1889 Jul 25, TLS, 1 p (Box 2)
- S.S. McClure to House 1889 Jul 30, TLS, 1 p (Box 2)
- T.J. Nakagawa to House 1889 Jul 30, ALS, 2 p (Box 2)
- F. Brinkley to House 1889 Aug 20, ALS, 3 p (Box 2)
- S.S. McClure to House 1889 Aug 21, TLS, 1 p (Box 2)
- S.S. McClure to House 1889 Aug 26, TLS, 1 p (Box 2)
- Robert Belford to House 1889 Sep 9, TLS, 1 p (Box 2)
- A. Sato to House 1889 Sep 13, ALS, 1 p (Box 2)
- S.S. McClure to House 1889 Sep 19, TLS, 1 p (Box 2)
- S.S. McClure to House 1889 Sep 24, TLS, 1 p (Box 2)
- E.L. Burlingame to House 1889 Sep 25, TLS, 2 p (Box 2)
- E.L. Burlingame to House 1889 Oct 17, TLS, 1 p (Box 2)
- S.S. McClure to House 1889 Oct 21, TLS, 1 p (Box 2)
- D. Nicholson to House 1889 Nov 4, TNS (Box 2)
- Rollin M. Morgan to House 1889 Nov 13, ALS, 3 p (Box 2)
- B.S. Balestier to House 1889 Nov 13, TLS, 1 p (Box 2)
- B.S. Balestier to House 1889 Nov 15, TLS, 1 p (Box 2)
- F. Brinkley to House 1889 Nov 21, ALS, 1 p (Box 2)
- E.L. Burlingame to House 1889 Dec 2, TLS, 2 p (Box 2)
- S.S. McClure to House 1889 Dec 11, TLS, 1 p (Box 2)
- E.L. Burlingame to House 1889 Dec 17, TLS, 1 p (Box 2)
- S.S. McClure to House 1889 Dec 30, TLS, 1 p (Box 2)
- Rollin M. Morgan to House 1890 Jan 6, ANS (Box 2)
- Scribner's to House 1890 Jan 7, form letter (Box 2)
- E.L. Burlingame to House 1890 Jan 14, TLS, 1 p (Box 2)
- Jas. F. Hood to Rollin M. Morgan 1890 Jan 27, TL [copy], 1 p (Box 2)
- George Spinney to House 1890 Jan 28, ALS, 1 p (Box 2)
- Daniel Frohman to House 1890 Feb 24, ANS (Box 2)
- E.L. Burlingame to House 1890 Feb 25, TNS (Box 2)
- Scribner's to House 1890 Feb 28, form letter, 1 p (Box 2)
- House to Rollins M. Morgan 1890 Mar 2, ALS, 2 p (Box 2)
- A.B. Starey to House 1890 Mar 4, ALS, 2 p (Box 2)
- F. Brinkley to House 1890 Mar 8, ALS, 2 p (Box 2)
- Harper & Brothers to House 1890 Mar 11, form letter, 1 p (Box 2)
- F.W. King to House 1890 Mar 15, TLS, 2 p (Box 2)
- Herbert L. Flint to House 1890 Mar 27, ALS, 1 p (Box 2)
- Daniel Frohman to House 1890 Mar 27, TNS (Box 2)
- Edmund Gerson to House 1890 Mar 28, ANS (Box 2)
- Mrs. E. Jeffryes Lindsay to House 1890 Mar 31, ALS, 1 p (Box 2)
- E.L. Burlingame to House 1890 Apr 24, TNS (Box 2)
- Olive Logan Sikes to Miss House [1890 Jun 2], ALS, 1 p (Box 2)
- Ned House to "Claxton" 1890 Jun 10, ALS, 2 p (Box 2)
- H.A. D'Arcy to House 1890 Aug 22, ALS, 4 p (Box 2)
- A.R. Spofford to House 1890 Sep 2, NS (Box 2)
- H.A. D'Arcy to House 1890 Sep 17, ALS, 7 p (Box 2)
- H.A. D'Arcy to House 1890 Sep 24, ALS, 10 p (Box 2)
- S.S. McClure to House 1890 Sep 24, TNS (Box 2)
- Dr. Carl Ludwig Barnay to House 1890 Sep 28, ALS, 3 p (Box 2)
- S.S. McClure to House 1890 Oct 7, TLS, 1 p (Box 2)
- S.S. McClure to House 1890 Oct 16, TLS, 1 p (Box 2)
- Louis Barrett to House 1890 Oct 17, ALS, 4 p (Box 2)
- S.S. McClure to House 1890 Oct 20, TLS, 1 p (Box 2)
- [S.S. McClure] to House 1890 Oct 22, TNS (Box 2)
- E.H.H. sample alterations in Prince & P[ca. 1890 Oct], AN (Box 2)
- E.H.H. extracts from Clemens' letters [ca. 1890], AN (Box 2)
- H.B. Davis to House 1890 Dec 11, telegram (Box 2)
- H.B. Davis to House 1890 Dec 17, telegram (Box 2)
- Rollin M. Morgan to House 1891 Jan 13, TLS, 1 p (Box 2)
- editors of Youths' Companion to House 1891 Jul 30, AL, 3 p (Box 3)
- Harper & Brothers to House 1891 Aug 10, form letter, 1 p (Box 3)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1891 Aug 15, ALS, 2 p (Box 3)
- John Howard Child to House 1891 Aug 27, ALS, 4 p (Box 3)
- A.R. Spofford to House 1891 Sep 3, ANS (Box 3)
- Daniel Frohman to House 1891 Sep 17, ANS (Box 3)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1891 Oct 2, 2 ALS, 3 p (Box 3)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1891 Oct 8, ALS, 2 p (Box 3)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1891 Oct 23, ALS, 1 p (Box 3)
- A.B. Starey to House 1891 Oct 23, ALS, 4 p (Box 3)
- A.B. Starey to House 1891 Oct 27, ALS, 3 p (Box 3)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1891 Oct [28], ALS, 2 p (Box 3)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1891 Nov 5, ALS, 2 p (Box 3)
- Joseph W. Harper to House 1891 Nov 17, ALS, 2 p (Box 3)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1891 Nov 18, ALS, 1 p (Box 3)
- A.B. Starey to House 1891 Nov 20, ALS, 3 p (Box 3)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1891 Nov 24, ALS, 1 p (Box 3)
- A.B. Starey to House 1891 Nov 24, ALS, 3 p (Box 3)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1891 Nov 25, ALS, 1 p (Box 3)
- G.W. Lynch to House 1891 Nov 25, ALS, 1 p (Box 3)
- Joseph W. Harper to House 1891 Nov 28, ALS, 4 p (Box 3)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1891 Dec 7, ALS, 1 p (Box 3)
- [Saidie Day] to Koto House 1891 Dec 10, AL, init., 3 p (Box 3)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1891Dec 10, 2 ALS, 5 p (Box 3)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1891 Dec 16, ALS, 1 p (Box 3)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1891 Dec 17, ALS, 1 p (Box 3)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1891 Dec 19, ALS, 1 p (Box 3)
- E.L. Burlingame to House 1891 Dec 23, TLS, 1 p (Box 3)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1891 Dec 26, ALS, 2 p (Box 3)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1891 Dec 30, ALS, 1 p (Box 3)
- Baron (?) Saigo to House [in Japanese] 1891 Jan 1, AL[S], 1 p (Box 3)
- T. Saigo to House ["translation"] 1891 Jan 1, [A?]L[S?], 1 p. (Box 3)
- A.B. Starey to House 1891 Jan 8, ALS, 2 p (Box 3)
- Rollin M. Morgan to House 1891 Jan 12, ALS, 1 p (Box 3)
- Harper & Brothers to House 1891 Jan 13, form letter, 1 p (Box 3)
- Paul Fuller (Coudert Brothers) to House 1891 Jan 16, TLS, 2 p (Box 3)
- Paul Fuller to House 1891Jan 19, ALS, 1 p (Box 3)
- Morgan & Ives to House 1891 Jan 20, TLS, 1 p (Box 3)
- House: notes on dispute with M & Ives [?] [ca. 1891 Jan 20], AN (Box 3)
- Paul Fuller to House 1891 Jan 22, ALS, 1 p (Box 3)
- Paul Fuller to House 1891 Jan 24, TLS, 3 p (Box 3)
- Coudert Brothers to Morgan & Ives [ca. 1891 Jan 24], AL Copy, frag., 1 p (Box 3)
- Paul Fuller to House 1891 Jan 26, 2 ALS, 2 p (Box 3)
- Paul Fuller to House 1891 Jan 27, ALS, 2 p (Box 3)
- Harper & Brothers to House 1891 Jan 27, form letter, 1 p (Box 3)
- Paul Fuller to House 1891 Feb 2, ALS, 1 p (Box 3)
- Morgan & Ives to House 1891 Feb 3, ALS, 1 p (Box 3)
- Paul Fuller to House 1891 Feb 4, ALS, 1 p (Box 3)
- Morgan & Ives to Coudert Brothers 1891 Feb 16, ADS, 2 p (Box 3)
- E.L. Burlingame to House 1891 Feb 16, TLS, 1 p (Box 3)
- Paul Fuller to House 1891 Feb 18, ALS, 1 p (Box 3)
- Harper & Brothers to House 1891 Feb 24, form letter, 1 p (Box 3)
- Paul Fuller to House 1891 Feb 25, TLS, 2 p (Box 3)
- Paul Fuller to House 1891 Feb 26, ALS, 1 p (Box 3)
- Paul Fuller to House 1891 Mar 10, ALS, 1 p (Box 3)
- Paul Fuller to House 1891 Mar 12, TLS, 1 p (Box 3)
- Paul Fuller to House 1891 Mar 13, ALS, 1 p (Box 3)
- George Brush (Coudert Brothers) to House 1891 Apr 1, TLS, 2 p (Box 3)
- Coudert Brothers to House 1891 Apr 3, ALS, 1 p (Box 3)
- A.B. Starey to House 1891 Apr 17, ALS, 1 p (Box 3)
- Paul Fuller to House 1891 Apr 25, TLS, 3 p (Box 3)
- Paul Fuller to House 1891 May 1, TLS, 2 p (Box 3)
- Charles E. LeBarbier 1891 May 1, S receipt, 1 p (Box 3)
- George Brush to House 1891 May 12, ALS, 1 p (Box 3)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1891 May 18, ALS, 2 p (Box 3)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1891 Jun 1, ALS, 1 p (Box 3)
- D. Nicholson to House 1891 Jun 9, TNS (Box 3)
- A.B. Starey to House 1891 Jun 12, ALS, 1 p (Box 3)
- Ned House to "Claxton" [1890 Jun 12?], ALS, 1 p (Box 3)
- A.B. Starey to House 1891 Jun 14, ALS, 1 p (Box 3)
- Harper & Brothers to House 1891 Jun 16, form letter, 1 p (Box 3)
- Harper & Brothers to House 1891 Jun 23, form letter, 1 p (Box 3)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1891 Jun 30, ALS, 1 p (Box 3)
- Paul Fuller to House 1891 Jun 30, ALS, 2 p (Box 3)
- George Brush to House 1891 Jun 30, ALS, 1 p (Box 3)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1891 Jul 1, ALS, 1 p (Box 3)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1891 Jul 13, 2 ALS, 2 p (Box 3)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1891 Jul 16, ALS, 1 p (Box 3)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Jan 2, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Jan 5, ALS, 2 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Jan 16, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Jan 19, ALS, 2 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Jan 23, ALS, 4 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Jan 25, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Jan 28, ALS, 2 p (Box 4)
- [Saidie Day] to Koto House 1892 Jan, AL initialed, 5 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Feb 3, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Feb 6, telegram (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Feb 9, telegram (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Feb 9, ALS, 4 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Feb 12, ALS, 2 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Feb 12, ALS, 2 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Feb 16, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Feb 17, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Feb 20, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Feb 23, telegram (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Feb 24, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Feb 27, telegram (Box 4)
- Virginia [Yerson] to Koto House [1892 Feb], ALS, 5 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Mar 1, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Mar 3, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Mar 9, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Mar 12, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Mar 22, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Mar 29, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Mar 30, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Aoki to Koto House [in Japanese] [1892 Mar], AL[S}, 1 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Apr 9, ALS, 2 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Apr 23, ALS, 2 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Apr 9-30, 3 ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Alice Hausell to "Dear Toorsy" [1892] Apr 16, ALS, 2 p (Box 4)
- Mrs. Hara to Koto House [1892] Apr 16, ALS, 4 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 May 4, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 May 10, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Richard H. Mitchell to Charles LeBarbier 1892 May 10, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 May 12, 2 ALS, 4 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 May 14, ALS, 2 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 May 23, telegram (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 May 27, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Aoki to Koto House [in Japanese] [1892 May 28], AL[S?], 1 p (Box 4)
- Annette Connors to Koto House 1892 Jun 1, ALS, 2 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Jun 3, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Jun 4, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Jun 8, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- editor of St. Nicholas to House 1892 Jun 10, TL, 2 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Jun 11, ALS, 2 p (Box 4)
- Mrs. Hara to Koto House [in Japanese] 1892 Jun 12, AL[S?], 2 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Jun 13, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Jun 16, telegram (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Jun 16, ALS, 2 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Jun 17, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- H. Villard to House 1892 Jun 17, ALS, 2 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Jun 20, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- James Janeway to House 1892 Jun 22, ALS, 2 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Jun 25, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Jun 27, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Harper & Brothers to House 1892 Jul 9, AL, 1 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Jul 12, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Charles E. LeBarbier to House 1892 Jul 13, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Donalea Downie to Koto House 18[9?]2 July, ALS, 2 p (Box 4)
- Harper & Brothers to House 1892 Aug 2, TL, 1 p (Box 4)
- Harper & Brothers to House 1892 Aug 8, TL, 1 p (Box 4)
- Harper & Brothers to House 1892 Aug 10, TL, 1 p (Box 4)
- Harper & Brothers to House 1892 Aug 17, TL, 1 p (Box 4)
- Harper & Brothers to House 1892 Aug 19, TN, 1 p (Box 4)
- Harper & Brothers to House 1892 Aug 23, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Harper & Brothers to House 1892 Aug 29, TLS, 1 p (Box 4)
- "the Editor," [Harper & Bros.] to House 1892 Aug 30, TN, 1 p (Box 4)
- Harper & Brothers to House 1892 Sep 14, TLS, 1 p (Box 4)
- S.S. McClure to House 1892 Sep 30, TNS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Inouye Kaoru to House 1892 Oct 26, ALS, 2 p (Box 4)
- Y. Uchida to House 1892 Nov 21, ALS, 3 p (Box 4)
- Harper & Brothers to House 1892 Dec 6, TL, 1 p (Box 4)
- Mrs. Nelson D'Apery to Koto House 1892, ALS, 3 p (Box 4)
- E.S. Marston to Koto House 1893 Mar 14, TLS, 1 p (Box 4)
- F. Brinkley to House 1893 Mar 17, ALS, 2 p (Box 4)
- [S.S. McClure, Ltd.] to House 1893 Apr 27, ALS, 2 p (Box 4)
- A.C. Cary to House 1893 May 3, ALS, 2 p (Box 4)
- A.C. Cary to House 1893 May 10, ANS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Ruralf Dittrich to House 1893 May 19, ALS, 2 p (Box 4)
- F. Brinkley to House [1893 Jun 5], ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- F. Brinkley to House [1893 Jun 23], ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- F. Brinkley to House [1893 Jun] Friday, ALS, 4 p (Box 4)
- F. Brinkley to House [1893 Jul 2], ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- E.L. Burlingame to House 1893 Jul 28, TLS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Harper & Brothers to House 1893 Aug 3, voucher, 2 p (Box 4)
- -- Gatto (Harper & Brothers) to House 1893 Aug 10, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- F. Brinkley to House [1893 Aug], ALS, 2 p (Box 4)
- F. Brinkley to House [1893 Oct 21], ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Harper & Brothers to House 1893 Dec 4, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Ruralf Dittrich to House 1893 Dec 13, ALS, 6 p (Box 4)
- Lucy Burditt to House 1893 Dec 19, ALS, 6 p (Box 4)
- F. Brinkley to House [1894] Jan 30, ALS, 3 p (Box 4)
- F. Brinkley to House [1894 Feb 16], ALS, 2 p (Box 4)
- Ruralf Dittrich to House 1894 Apr 10, ALS, 4 p (Box 4)
- F. Brinkley to House [1894 Apr 11], ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Ruralf Dittrich to House 1894 May 15, ALS, 3 p (Box 4)
- F. Brinkley to House [1894 May 19], ACardS (Box 4)
- Ruralf Dittrich to House 1894 May 20, ALS, 4 p (Box 4)
- Ruralf Dittrich to House 1894 Jun 15, ALS, 7 p (Box 4)
- F. Brinkley to House [1894 Jun 16], ALS, 2 p (Box 4)
- F. Brinkley to House [1894 Jun 18], ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Ruralf Dittrich to House 1894 Jun 29, ALS, 5 p (Box 4)
- Ruralf Dittrich to House 1894 Jul 21, ALS, 4 p (Box 4)
- F. Brinkley to House [1894] Sep 11, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Lieutenant T.H. James to House 1894 Oct 10, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- T. Hayashi to House [1894] Oct 20, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- T. Hayashi to House [1894] Oct 22, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Col. Yamanouchi to House 1894 Oct 29, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- Harper & Brothers to House 1894 Nov 5, ALS, 1 p (Box 4)
- The World to House 1894 Nov 13, telegram carbon (Box 4)
- The World to House 1894 Nov 15, telegram carbon (Box 5)
- The World to House 1894 Nov 23, telegram (Box 5)
- R.A. Farrelly to House 1894 Nov 26, ALS, 1 p (Box 5)
- F. Brinkley to House [1894 Dec 10], ALS, 1 p (Box 5)
- The World to House 1894 Dec 13, telegram (Box 5)
- Amy Burditt Child to House 1894 Dec 18, ALS, 2 p (Box 5)